<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2019-06-05T08:20:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Final Project</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/hcde598/2019/06/05/final-project.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/hcde598/2019/06/05/final-project.html</id>
    <published>2019-06-05T08:20:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-06-05T14:55:41-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/final.gif" alt="Testing out the cam on the servo" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Final piece&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="concept"&gt;Concept&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A shadowbox art piece that captures the sky over the Olympic Mountains. For reference: here is an image of sunrise over the Olympic Mountains from Capitol Hill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/sunrise.jpg" alt="Sunrise over the Olympics" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to use leds and different color and translucencies of acrylic to create this effect, and also move mountains! The initial idea to put three sets of mountains on cam was because the colors of mountains were not easily created by shining leds through acrylic. They're different colors at different times of the day, so why not have different sets of ranges move to accomodate that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/onshape-assembly.png" alt="OnShape Assembly" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;OnShape Assembly from Planning&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="bill-of-materials"&gt;Bill of Materials&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To complete this project, I ended up using:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 24" x 12" sheets of translucent white acrylic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 24" x 12" sheet of black acrylic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 12" x 12" sheets of clear blue acrylic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/4" diameter wood dowel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gray PLA Filament&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 8' x 6" poplar board&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 36" x 3/4" straight dowels&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nails &amp;amp; Nail gun&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wood glue&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 angle braces + 4 screws each&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 individually addressable LED string&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 Arduino Uno&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 5V batter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 5V outlet to battery pack connector with on/off switch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="original-bill-of-materials-from-project-planning"&gt;Original Bill of Materials from Project Planning:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/bom.png" alt="Original Bill of Materials" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="file-creation"&gt;File creation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How I created everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="led-grid"&gt;1. LED Grid&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started out from the back of the piece by creating the grid each LED would sit in by parametrically generating circles that were the diameter of the LEDs. I did this in case I needed to quickly change the diameter after doing a test run of laser cutting the acrylic to account for tolerance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/grasshopper.png" alt="Grasshopper" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then baked the light cut outs and exported everything as a .dxf file to import it with all my laser cut pieces into Illustrator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="mountains-and-foreground"&gt;2. Mountains and Foreground&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create the mountains, I imported a screencapture from the app PeakFinder on my phone into Illustrator. I then used the image trace feature to turn the screencapture into a vector and manually isolated the silhouette of the Olympic range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/peakfinder-screenshot.jpg" alt="Peakfinder screenshot" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="cam-mechanism"&gt;3. Cam mechanism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created the Cam Mechanism in OnShape by importing the .dxf of the light grid and the mountain range I created in Illustrator. I then adjusted everything on an axel that was the size of the 1/4" wooden dowel I would use in the assembly to get the right shape. I exported the face of the cam as a .dxf to import into my laser cutting file in Illustrator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same assembly, I created followers which would attach to the laser cut mountain rangers to give more stability as the cam rotated. I exported these as .stl files to import to Dremel's 3D printing software to print.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I created an axel holder for the front of the mechanism which would be glued onto the back side of the foreground to provide proper placement for the cam mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/cams-onshape.png" alt="OnShape Assembly" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="leds"&gt;4. LEDs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I created a &lt;a href="https://github.com/kfrank/gitbit"&gt;program to create light sequences with LED strings&lt;/a&gt; in Arduino, I actually decided not to use it and opted for simpler code which would fade from blue to orange and then back. I mostly did this because I ran out of time at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://forum.arduino.cc/index.php?topic=418923.msg2886563#msg2886563"&gt;Reference code used&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="servo"&gt;Servo&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up attaching the cam to the servo and did a test through the Arduino examples, but didn't actually end up hooking this up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/cam.gif" alt="Testing out the cam on the servo" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="assembling"&gt;Assembling&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laser cutting and 3D printing went pretty smoothly. I actually showed up before our second to last class at the MILL and printed everything while no one was there. Nothing caught on fire, and when I had all my pieces stand up to test how they would look, I was pretty happy with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/testing-layers.JPG" alt="Visual Acrylic Layer test" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="laser-cutting"&gt;1. Laser cutting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used my old acrylic settings of 10 speed, 100 power, 50 frequency to cut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/laser-cut-mountains.JPG" alt="Mountains" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="d-printing"&gt;2. 3D printing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the printers I was using jammed halfway through printing the second cam, but we got it unstuck and started printing just fine again. Since I had some time, I pulled an arduino enclosure off of Thingaverse and printed the bottom of it so I could more easily connect my arduino the the back of the piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="frame"&gt;3. Frame&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now here's where things got tricky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved last Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All my stuff got packed up, I actually didn't lose anything from the this project, thankfully, but it was ALL OVER the place. There's still boxes everywhere in what will become my office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My original plan was the go to the Fluke Makerspace on Friday evening to attend the woodshop and then miter cut my wood and cut grooves in it (hopefully with a table saw).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I moved Friday and had my life upended, I missed out by like half an hour because of traffic from my new place. Awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My back up plan, however, was to visit the West Seattle Tool Library and rent a miter saw and a router to make the frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/tool-library.JPG" alt="Tool Library" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, despite making a very cool guide for my router, I had way too many things nailed down and I still failed at getting stright grooves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/failed-routing.JPG" alt="Failed routing" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my next attempt, I cut some grooves using my Dremel multi-tool in wood. They were grooves all right, but not straight, and definitely didn't fit any acrylic in place. That idea also got scraped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/grooves.JPG" alt="Grooves" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the third attempt, I went back to Home Depot and picked up some more wood and straight dowels to use to create grooves. I figured I could use my nail gun and some wood glue to get the dowels in place to hold the acrylic. Except my miter saw was weird and I couldn't figure out how to change the angle of the blade since my wood was now 6", too tall to fit under the saw. I just made some straight cuts instead and moved on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/grooves-take-2.JPG" alt="Third attempt" /&gt;
&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/testing-fit.JPG" alt="Testing straight dowels" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yay, it finally worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="post-process"&gt;4. Post-process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/mirror-coating.JPG" alt="Spray painting the LED grid" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I was going crazy with the saw and some wood glue, I was waiting for some spray paint to dry on the LED side of my LED grid. This gives the acrylic a much more reflective surface to have the light bounce off of. Which I needed because I used really huge LEDs instead of being a smart person and just ordering new strings with small ones and using more of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="putting-it-together"&gt;5. Putting it together&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the LEDs got popped into their individual holes in the grid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/assembling-leds.JPG" alt="LEDs" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each layer of acrylic got fit into the sides with the grooves and then the bottom was nailed on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/layers.JPG" alt="Layers" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would've been great, but I ended up breaking my cam axel assembling everything. Since I couldn't find my dowels because of moving, I just decided to go with non-moving ranges and glued them into place at different heights to create a nice effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/cam-underneath.JPG" alt="Cams" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/cam-servo-attachment.JPG" alt="Cam attachment" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I threw up the NeoPixel test to see how it would look. Ok, the light goes through the acrylic, but again, since I wasn't being a sane person, the lights gave an abstract grid-y look instead of the fluid gradient look I was going for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/testing-leds.JPG" alt="Testing out the leds" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I nailed on the top instead and threw up a blue to orange color swipe with NeoPixel and called this prototype done. Even though it's not exactly what I was going for, I still think it looks cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/final5.JPG" alt="Testing out the leds" /&gt;
&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/final2.jpg" alt="Testing out the leds" /&gt;
&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment7/final1.JPG" alt="Testing out the leds" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="reflection"&gt;Reflection&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-wood-frame"&gt;1. The wood frame&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe this would've been easier if I would've been able to go to Fluke all along, but I wouldn't have done this the way I did. Improvising cost my hours worth of time I wasn't expecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="cam-followers-longer"&gt;2. Cam followers longer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I tested the cam mechanism, the mountains lifted and lowered, but weren't exactly uniformly horizontal. I would've definitely made the followers longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="small-led-strip"&gt;3. Small LED strip&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using smaller LED strips would've made the gradient animation much more subtle and give the effect I was going for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="experiment-with-led-lighting-from-bottom-on-acrylic"&gt;4. Experiment with LED lighting from bottom on acrylic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also came across this method in my research, but wanted to do something different. This technique would've been great to experiment with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="source-files"&gt;Source Files&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="onshape"&gt;OnShape&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cad.onshape.com/documents/a8e1af7107f956e7db86eb20/w/049e752049c02e10ec8a1439/e/26cb20b70adedc1d48e5dbd8"&gt;Onshape Assembly &amp;amp; Modeling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="grasshoppercad"&gt;Grasshopper/CAD&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LED Grid&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/hcde598/documentation/final/working-files/light-grid.gh"&gt;Parametric LED grid – Grasshopper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/hcde598/documentation/final/working-files/light-grid.3dm"&gt;Parametric LED grid – Rhino&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mountain Ranges&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/hcde598/documentation/final/mountain-black.ai"&gt;Mountains&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="laser-cutting-files"&gt;Laser cutting files&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/hcde598/documentation/final/LASER_CUT.ai"&gt;Illustrator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Light Grid
&lt;a href="/hcde598/documentation/final/exports/01-light-grid.dxf"&gt;.dxf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cam
&lt;a href="/hcde598/documentation/final/exports/3-Cam.dxf"&gt;.dxf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mountain Ranges
&lt;a href="/hcde598/documentation/final/exports/3-mountains.dxf"&gt;.dxf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foreground
&lt;a href="/hcde598/documentation/final/exports/foreground.dxf"&gt;.dxf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="d-model-files"&gt;3D model files&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Axel Holder
&lt;a href="/hcde598/documentation/final/D3_axel-holder.gcode"&gt;.gcode&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/hcde598/documentation/final/exports/axel-holder.stl"&gt;.stl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follower
&lt;a href="/hcde598/documentation/final/D3_PRINT.gcode"&gt;.gcode&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/hcde598/documentation/final/exports/3-follower.stl"&gt;.stl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arduino Enclosure
&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=8&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwj14Z2PqtPiAhXEGTQIHZ8-D7UQFjAHegQIBxAB&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.thingiverse.com%2Fthing%3A628929&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw0RH_-KixUyVANXXO82UBWg"&gt;via Thingiverse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Casting Rockets</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/hcde598/2019/05/17/casting-rockets.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/hcde598/2019/05/17/casting-rockets.html</id>
    <published>2019-05-16T19:20:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-05-26T10:32:22-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I made Saturn V rockets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="documentation"&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.thingiverse.com/thing:3416703"&gt;.stl model (sourced off Thingaverse)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/hcde598/documentation/casting/saturnv-mold.3dm"&gt;Rhino mold&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/hcde598/documentation/casting/saturnv-mold-2.stl"&gt;Stl mold&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/hcde598/documentation/casting/D3_saturnv-mold-3d.gcode"&gt;Gcode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="unused-documentation"&gt;Unused documentation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/hcde598/documentation/casting/saturnv-mold.f3d"&gt;Fusion 360&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="process"&gt;Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started out first creating the mold model in Rhino with the intention of milling on machinable wax. When I was searching around, I found out that NASA has a lot of 3D models available already. I downloaded the Saturn V rocket, but realized that it was actually a model that contained all of the separate stages of the rocket. Instead of playing puzzle in three dimensions, I went to thingaverse and borrowed a 3D model of the Saturn V rocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Rhino, I imported the rocket mesh and then created a box around it that was approximately the size of my piece of machineable wax, and then positioned the rocket so that half of it was submerged into the bottom of the box. I decided to create two halves of the rockets to speed up the amount of rockets I could cast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment6/rhino.png" alt="Creating the mold in Rhino" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then exported the mold and opened it in Fusion 360 to create toolpaths. After creating a toolpath only using a 1/8 flat mill, I realized that I would not get the level of detail I wanted. I went back to Fusion 360 and added two more tools: a 1/16 &amp;amp; a 1/32. When I imported all three of these toolpaths into Bantam Tools, it estimated it would take 9 hours to complete. Not cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment6/bantam-tools.png" alt="All three toolpaths in Bantam" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided quickly to not even attempt milling on machinable wax. I then modified my mold model in Rhino to decrease the printed material on the bottom of the box so that it would print quicker. When I imported the model into the Dremel tool, it estimated roughly 3 hours. Much better. I used similar settings to my last print: Medium Quality at 0.2mm and 20% infill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment6/3D-print.png" alt="Model in Dremel Tools" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then sent my gcode file to the Dremel printers at the MILL with 230° filament and 55° plate settings. It printed great in about three hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment6/IMG_2629.JPG" alt="3D printing" /&gt;
&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment6/IMG_2630.JPG" alt="3D print mold" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back home, I mixed equal parts of both liquids to make the Oomoo mold. Originally I was thinking, oh great, since I have two sides, I might be able to put them together to make a two part mold. Unfortunately, the Ooomoo wasn't quite precise when drying, even though the 3d print looked much more precise. I decided at that point to not attempt to create a sprue on these molds and just stick with flat rockets which would look great on a tabletop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment6/IMG_2638.JPG" alt="Setting the mold" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used a small, very dull paring knife to carefully pull my mold out. Part of one mold didn't quite set completely on one of the engines, but it actually didn't end up mattering when I went to cast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mixed 3 parts plaster to 1 part water and filled my molds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment6/IMG_2640.JPG" alt="Filled molds" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took some thought to know how to seperate the dried plaster from the mold without breaking the plaster. I figured out that pulling the mold apart on the sides of the rocket first and then the top and bottom helped get them out the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment6/IMG_2662.JPG" alt="Plaster Saturn V" /&gt;
&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment6/IMG_2679.JPG" alt="Multiples" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="reflection"&gt;Reflection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make the model even more smooth, I probably would sand down the rocket inside the model. I'd also want to print one rocket much larger to make setting the plaster and getting it out of the mold easier.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>CNC Milled Box</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/hcde598/2019/05/11/cnc-milled-box.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/hcde598/2019/05/11/cnc-milled-box.html</id>
    <published>2019-05-11T08:02:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-05-26T10:32:22-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I decided to make a box with tabs for the sides to fit together and grooves for the top and bottom. This allows the top to slide out to access the contents of the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment5/IMG_2614.jpeg" alt="Sketching out the plan" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="documentation"&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="rhino--illustrator"&gt;Rhino &amp;amp; Illustrator&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/hcde598/documentation/cnc-box/cnc-box.3dm"&gt;Rhino&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/hcde598/documentation/cnc-box/cnc-box.Ai"&gt;Illustrator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="bantam-tools"&gt;Bantam Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/hcde598/documentation/cnc-box/side-long-2.btm"&gt;Long Sides with Tab Cutouts and Grooves&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/hcde598/documentation/cnc-box/side-short-2.btm"&gt;Short Sides with Tabs and Grooves&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/hcde598/documentation/cnc-box/topbottom.btm"&gt;Top and Bottom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="making-the-shapes"&gt;Making the shapes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started out generating the shapes in Grasshopper so I could control the size better. From there, I baked all the sides in Rhino, filleted the tabs, and then created the top and bottom pieces based on the length of the groove plus an allowance for material thickness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment5/grasshopper.png" alt="Starting in Grasshopper" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Generating box sides in Grasshopper&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment5/rhino.png" alt="Shapes built in Rhino" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;From top left, clockwise: Top of box, bottom of box, short side (purple line is a groove), long side (purple lines are grooves), short side.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up modifying my original side design allow the top to overhang the short side with the cut out tab to make sliding the top out easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="setting-up-files"&gt;Setting up files&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I exported the shapes in Rhino and opened them in Illustrator so that I could make detailed modifications and then export each side as an svg. When saving svgs, I decided to save each shape part as an individual svg to import into the Bantam Tools software. This also allowed me to set different mill tool preferences for each part. The tab cutouts on the long sides needed a 1/64 size mill tool while the rest of the parts could be done mostly with a 1/16 size. I also left a little overhang on the engraved cutouts so that the top would be able to slide properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment5/bantam.png" alt="Short sides in Bantam" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The short sides with a little overhand for the groove.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was actually really straightforward to set up the mill and put in my pieces. I didn't have any problems here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment5/IMG_2608.jpg" alt="Mill milling" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment5/IMG_2607.jpg" alt="Cutting out the large sides" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="box-assembled"&gt;Box, Assembled&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Magically, all my math was correct and the box fit together. &lt;i class="em em-tada"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment5/IMG_2609.jpg" alt="Final box, together" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment5/IMG_2610.jpg" alt="Top" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment5/IMG_2611.jpg" alt="Top pulled out" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Gear Assembly</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/hcde598/2019/05/05/gear-assembly.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/hcde598/2019/05/05/gear-assembly.html</id>
    <published>2019-05-05T13:48:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-05-26T10:32:22-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For this assignment, I had two goals in mind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spend the least amount of time in the MILL.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start with a base assembly that fulfills the assignment and then add a challenging stretch goal on to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn't want a repeat of last week where I spent 9 and a half hours in the MILL and had some strong anxiety. This week, I only spent 3 hours in the mill and most of that time I was working while waiting for my 3D print to finish. I probably only spent 30 minutes actively laser cutting or setting up the 3D printer, which I'd call a win based on good planning and some luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="documentation"&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cad.onshape.com/documents/1733a3f48a16a99259e4a93e/w/6e427e999e67f320646f689c/e/16f4c02966ac4d06ccea2547"&gt;OnShape Model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="documentation/to_laser_cut.ai"&gt;Laser Cut File&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="documentation/D3_base.gcode"&gt;3D Printed Base&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="documentation/D3_center-gear.gcode"&gt;3D Printed Gear&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="design"&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this assignment, I first started with a two part gear assembly with one 3d printed gear and one laser cut gear. I intended to laser cut all flat parts and 3D print other parts. The smaller center gear was to be 3D printed because I designed it with a cylinder on the top which would fit over a dowel (the point of rotation origin) and connect to a hand turner on top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then added on to the assembly by making it a three part gear assembly with an outer internal spur gear with arrows attached along the outside. These arrows would rotate on a pin and would flip over when the encountered a long dowel sticking out underneath and past the outer gear. In the below screenshot, the part to the left of the yellow arrow is the long dowel used to flip the arrow's direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment4/onshape.png" alt="Creating the parts in OnShape" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;All the parts mostly aligned&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found OnShape much easier to use and design in than Rhino. It seemed to mesh more with how my brain things through assembling parts. I especially liked that you could test out all the parts before even fabricating them, something I tried to do in Rhino but couldn't. Below, you can see the three gears spinning together in the assembly. (I didn't connect the arrows to the outer wheel here.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment4/assembly1.gif" alt="Creating the assembly in OnShape" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Testing out the gears.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to have all the parts listed automatically in a bill of materials helped me a lot in keeping organized and having a plan for when I got to the MILL. I added a column for how each part would be fabricated (or if it was sourced), and then another for any post-processing I planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment4/bom.png" alt="Bill of Materials" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Listing out methods of fabrication and post-processing for all the parts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="fabrication-and-assembly"&gt;Fabrication and assembly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started the 3D printed base first when I got to the MILL since that would take the longest. Surprisingly, I didn't have any prints fail!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment4/IMG_2521.JPG" alt="3D printing the base" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Base with slots for two pegs for the inner gears.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I exported all the flat pieces as .DXF files and assembled them all into Illustrator together. Like my previous projects, I laser cut on wood again because that's what I had already available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment4/laser-cut.png" alt="Laser cut" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Flat pieces to laser cut from wood.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up sourcing some &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07H58Z6HH/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_asin_title_o00_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1"&gt;wooden dowels&lt;/a&gt; that were 10mm in diameter because that's what the default center bore diameter happened to be in OnShape. These fit really nice in the base. I ended up sanding down part of the middle dowel to make the spinning interaction even more smooth. Yay for having wooden dowels to do this with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The major trouble I encountered was that the piece I laser cut for the hand turner wasn't quite large enough to fit over the top of the 3D printed inner gear. Even after sanding down the hole for the turner and the outside of the gear, I thought I got it to be enough but broke the piece trying to fit it on top. &lt;i class="em em-frowning"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Next time I'll probably just make both parts together and 3D print them both so I know they'll be the right dimensions. It's a bit hard to tell when you're trying not to wait 2 hours for a 3D print to finish before laser cutting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good thing the assembly still works pretty well by spinning the inner gear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment4/IMG_2532.JPG" alt="Inner gear" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;You can see where I sanded down the top of the inner gear to get the turner to fit before I broke that part.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment4/2-gear.gif" alt="Inner gears" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The gear assembly in action. Pretty satisfying to spin! I’ll say definitely intentional, smooth, and robust. &lt;i class="em em-smile"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="stretch-goals"&gt;Stretch goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the challenge part of this, I wanted to see if I could get the interally toothed gear working to flip some arrows. Unfortunately, since I already cut out the piece, it was hard for me to find true center. I used some thread to find it and then confirmed with my calipers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was planning on screwing the piece to connect the outer gear to the center, but didn't anticipate my wood being so brittle. I splintered it too much and had to use wood glue and a clamp to attach this part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment4/IMG_2568.JPG" alt="Finding the center of the outer gear" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Using string to find the true center.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn't really have time to source pins to use, so I made do with some nails instead. I used a slightly larger drill bit than the nails so that the arrows could pivot. I messed up drilling straight through the center of the wood a few times (thicker wood would've helped here). I then attached a few of the arrows around the outer gear to test turning, though this too was hard due to how fragile the wooden gear was. I probably wouldn't use wood again for making small moving parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment4/IMG_2569.JPG" alt="Setting up the arrows" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Arrows drilled with nails as pins.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used a drill bit as my arrow turner instead of trying to find something to source since it was long enough and I knew it would stay put for me to test out the interaction. (You can see it sticking out of the peg in the base on the right in the below image.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment4/IMG_2594.JPG" alt="All the parts" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The major parts disassembled.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a bit of difficulty trying to figure out the proper point to put the pivot nails in the arrow. Some of them worked great, and others took more force to turn. Again, if I had more time for this assignment, I probably would've used a different material for the outer gear and the connectors to the arrows. I couldn't find any information on how to create this interaction in the assembly in OnShape. The software ignored objects colliding with one another, which is kind of the point of this interaction. Being able to prototype that would've saved me a lot of fiddling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see at the bottom of the below gif one of the arrows flipping over the drill bit turner. Yay, it works!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment4/outer-wheel.gif" alt="Spinning the wheel" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;This is really hard to spin and keep a camera straight at the same time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>3D + Lasercut Lamp</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/hcde598/2019/04/27/lamp.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/hcde598/2019/04/27/lamp.html</id>
    <published>2019-04-26T18:02:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-05-26T10:32:22-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For this project, I created a tall pendant lamp. The inside connector was 3D printed while the shade was laser cut on plywood with angled cut-outs. This transforms the light into nice patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to approach this by first tackling the 3D printing part of the project and then using the measurements from what I printed to laser cut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="d-printing-documentation"&gt;3D printing Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://klare.io/hcde598/documentation/lamp/2wheel.3dm"&gt;Rhino 3D model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://klare.io/hcde598/documentation/lamp/2wheel.3dm"&gt;STL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="laser-cutting-documentation"&gt;Laser Cutting Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://klare.io/hcde598/documentation/lamp/wood.3dm"&gt;Rhino model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://klare.io/hcde598/documentation/lamp/wood.AI"&gt;Illustrator printing file&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="first-attempt"&gt;First Attempt&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my first idea, I really wanted to see if I could reuse my LED light string I had previously used in Physical Computing. My Boyfriend and I had written a C++ program to create vectors of light sequences, so it would've been great to get this working again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment3/IMG_2465.JPG" alt="Using LED light string" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attempted to print connectors that would fit onto each led on the string and then hook onto a laser cut piece. Then each led + laser cut leaf could be assembled in a spiral pattern to create a lampshade. Would've been cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I was already in the MILL Thursday teaching 5th graders the User-Centered Design process for Engineering Discovery Days, I stayed after to start printing even though I didn't have a solid plan. Despite having a nicely printed test piece, printing other connectors was an utter failure. Lesson learned: don't try to print lots of little pieces because it's going to take forever or have some failure if you try to print them all at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set the printer to 235° for filament and 55° for build plate per the recommendation of the MILL staff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment3/connector.png" alt="Connector in Rhino at 4 different views" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Connector modeled in Rhino.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment3/IMG_2498.JPG" alt="Bad pieces" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Bad pieces that didn't print right.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if I &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; get a lot of these printed at the exact measurements I needed, I still needed to devise a way to piece together the lamp itself. I didn't have a great idea for that. After failing to print these connectors, and coming back from the MILL with pieces I had to Dremel (the tool, not the software) a good enough hole out of, I scraped all this work and started to think about the construction of lampshades instead. It really felt like 4 and a half hours of my life wasted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://klare.io/hcde598/documentation/lamp/lamp-connector.3dm"&gt;Rhino 3D model for connectors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="second-attempt"&gt;Second Attempt&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created a cylinder with spokes for the next attempt. At the end of each spoke is a "T" where I imagined the laser cut pieces could drop onto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment3/wheel.png" alt="Building the wheel and spoke idea instead" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Building the second model idea in Rhino&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first attempt to print this came out so very wrong. I went into the MILL Friday morning to set this to print and came back later in the day. The whole print broke apart when I was trying to get it off of the bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment3/IMG_2484.JPG" alt="Building the wheel and spoke idea instead" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Not cool. Another 1/2 a day wasted.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went back to Rhino and built another, beefier model that only had 6 spokes. If I was going to attempt this again, I wanted to be damn sure I could print something I could actually use.
I had created other versions of this that staggered the spokes in a spiral up the inner cylinder but didn't want to risk having any support structures fail in printing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment3/spiral.png" alt="Spiral model" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Double spiral model&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made sure everything was connected together with BooleanUnion in Rhino, exported to Dremel's software and double checked the layers with Joshua to make sure they'd print all as one object. We also swapped out the filament. This model finally print properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment3/IMG_2491.JPG" alt="Building the wheel and spoke idea instead" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Yay, success after 9 and a half hours in the MILL &lt;i class="em em-upside_down_face"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I laser cut each side of the shade on plywood I had sitting around in my place. There were some people at the MILL who had been laser engraving for hours on both printers and another person who's laser engraving was set to take another hour after that, so it was a PITA to wait around for that to finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really just wanted to be done at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I masked off the area to be laser cut and used the same settings as last time for wood: 10 speed, 100 power, 50 frequency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment3/laser-gif.gif" alt="Laser cutting the shade" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually really enjoyed that I could fit every laser cut piece onto one of the spokes for easy transport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment3/IMG_2497.JPG" alt="Building the wheel and spoke idea instead" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="future-considerations"&gt;Future considerations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would've been nice to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iterate on my 3d printed model by taking in every other spoke to the exact specification of the where the inset pieces sit.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;have created another "T" to sandwich the laser cut pieces on the spoke at the exact point.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Actually print the spiralized version of the model I created.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But after spending 9.5 hours in the MILL, I called this project done. There was way too much pressure to get something printed before the rush of a "Tuesday Night Crew". I failed my only class in undergrad because they ran out of materials for everyone to work with for the last two assignments and this felt a bit like I could've been on the edge of reliving that moment. Not exactly the best conditions to work creatively under.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would've liked to have completed this assignment with a longer time frame for ideation and exploration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment3/IMG_2494.jpg" alt="After laser cutting" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Using gravity keep things in place because it's a hanging lamp.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment3/IMG_2496.JPG" alt="After laser cutting" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Every other piece inset for more light effects.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment3/IMG_2502.jpg" alt="Assembled" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Parametric Kit</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/hcde598/2019/04/23/parametric-kit.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/hcde598/2019/04/23/parametric-kit.html</id>
    <published>2019-04-22T19:26:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-05-26T10:32:22-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It sticks together, yay &lt;i class="em em-smile"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://klare.io/hcde598/documentation/rhino-grasshopper/cutout-triangles-kit.3dm"&gt;Rhino file&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://klare.io/hcde598/documentation/rhino-grasshopper/cutout-triangles-kit.ai"&gt;Illustrator file&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://klare.io/hcde598/documentation/rhino-grasshopper/cutout-triangles-kit.gh"&gt;Grasshopper source code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment2/IMG_2461.jpg" alt="Assembled" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="designing-the-kit"&gt;Designing the kit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I turned to my own company, CodePen, for inspiration since there tend to be a lot of geometric designs created, even if they're mostly interactive. I thought this one was cool since it had sets of solid and outlined triangles intersected at seemingly random degrees. I used this concept to create triangles with random intersections which created cut-outs of various polygons inside a triangle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also had some plywood lying around from previous projects (much more than cardboard), so I used that with a new acrylic sheet to give the kit some color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="codepen" data-height="387" data-theme-id="0" data-default-tab="result" data-user="yuanchuan" data-slug-hash="YLyEvb" style="height: 387px; box-sizing: border-box; display: flex; align-items: center; justify-content: center; border: 2px solid black; margin: 1em 0; padding: 1em;" data-pen-title="Unicode triangles"&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href="https://codepen.io/yuanchuan/pen/YLyEvb/"&gt;
  Unicode triangles&lt;/a&gt; by yuanchuan (&lt;a href="https://codepen.io/yuanchuan"&gt;@yuanchuan&lt;/a&gt;)
  on &lt;a href="https://codepen.io"&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://static.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id="generating-the-shapes-with-grasshopper-in-rhino"&gt;Generating the shapes with Grasshopper in Rhino&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first attempt at this was to use triangulate to generate a grid of triangles and then use the first triangle's three points to calculate an inner triangle which was duplicated in a rectangular array. While this strategy did work and allowed me to keep the size relative for both triangles, it proved stressful when trying to generate notch connectors for every side of the larger triangle. (See details in the issues section below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I scrapped that idea and instead tried to approach this by creating one triangle from a polyline using trigonometry to make it perfectly equilateral. From there, I created notches with a slider to change the width corresponding to material thickness and polar arrayed the rectangular notches around the center of the triangle. I then used arrays to duplicate the triangles into a controlled grid set up to match my material size (12" x 12").&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This strategy worked much better for actually giving me shapes I could then manipulate and print from, but it still had a ton of issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="issues"&gt;Issues&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even as someone who thinks through problems for programming on a regular basis, there were things Grasshopper did that were highly annoying and I would’ve saved hours of my life just doing them in illustrator. I did countless hours of Googling and searching through the Grasshopper forums, like in real life as a developer but 10x worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment2/2zcjhn.jpg" alt="Confused Meme" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="i-classem-em-upsidedownfacei-triangulate-is-annoying"&gt;&lt;i class="em em-upside_down_face"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Triangulate is annoying&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using triangulate somehow made things extremely annoying. Generating notches for all the outer triangle sides required calculating the exact angle relative to X and corresponding each angle to a xy plane relative to the midpoint of each triangle edge. I actually &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; get this to work and generate triangles in the right places, but when I baked everything, I was given about 5x the amount of notches, most on top of one another. This would not have been great to send to a laser cutter, as it would've made passes for each drawn curve. Even debugging by getting the list length of variables at different steps didn't exactly lead to figuring out why I was getting so many notches. I probably spent 2-3 hours just trying to figure this out. It still didn't work when I turned graft off and collapsed the tree, so idk. &lt;i class="em em-woman-shrugging"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment2/notches-for-all.png" alt="Triangulate notches for all" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="i-classem-em-cryi-random-isnt-random-at-all"&gt;&lt;i class="em em-cry"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; "Random" isn't random at all&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my optimism, I wanted to use Grasshopper to generate everything in my design, including the bisecting lines for the inner triangles. The only issue was that I wanted this to be unique for every triangle, no matter how many triangles got generated. This is where I re-learned that every "random" function in programming isn't really random; it just chooses from a seemingly random list of numbers, but on each iteration, follows the same pattern. I also ran into this issue when working on my led light strip for Physical Prototyping. The screenshot below got pretty close, but it still wasn't the best. If you look closely, you definitely see a pattern. Also, wtf was up with the very last triangle getting ALL the lines. Not bisecting at all. &lt;i class="em em-woman-gesturing-no"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment2/randomize-lines.png" alt="&amp;quot;Randomizing&amp;quot; lines for inner triangle cut-outs" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="i-classem-em-woman-facepalmingi-fillet-does-all-corners"&gt;&lt;i class="em em-woman-facepalming"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Fillet does all corners&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; wanted to fillet the corners where the notches connect to make a smooth and satisfying connection when assembling the kit. Using the standard fillet function ended up filleting &lt;em&gt;ALL&lt;/em&gt; the corners, which would've meant a loose connection on the very inside of the notches. No good. I turned to using the other fillet function, which fillets on only one curve and set a Boolean list to specify which ones I wanted filleted. Turns out this creates a new curve for &lt;em&gt;EVERY&lt;/em&gt; filleted edge. Also no good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kind of just gave up on this one, though when I was in the makerspace printing, Andrew informed me that he used a triangle to trim the edges for a custom fillet. This seems like a much better approach to getting a fillet only on the outside, but doesn't still make any sense to me why you can't just modify the fillet function to do what you want. With Andrew's triangle cut-out approach, it did require setting an origin exactly at the midpoint and rotating it the correct degrees, but it worked much better. Since I was printing and spent hours in Grasshopper already, I decided to just cut fillets for the connectors in Illustrator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment2/custom-filleting-issue.png" alt="Custom Filleting Issue" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="grasshopper-take-two"&gt;Grasshopper take two&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From experiencing all these issues, I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; wanted to try to solve generating most everything parametrically in Grasshopper. I think my past failures were not fully understanding when to graft/simplify/flatten trees. When I redid everything with all my new knowledge from past failures, I had a much better time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment2/everything.png" alt="Triangle grid" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Yay, it all works much better not doing this at 1am.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="create-a-triangular-grid"&gt;1. Create a triangular grid&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I found the center of each triangle by separating the edges, finding the endpoints of each line, and using one side of the endpoint to calculate the center of each triangle. I set also inputs for each material thickness (I had three).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment2/inputs.png" alt="Triangle grid" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="scale-the-triangles-in-the-grid-to-create-inner-triangles"&gt;2. Scale the triangles in the grid to create inner triangles&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the grid as the base geometry, and then set the center using the above calculation to scale triangles down in size, creating inner triangles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment2/triangular.png" alt="Triangle grid scale" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="make-notches-for-connectors"&gt;3. Make notches for connectors&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the triangles in the grid are not in the same orientation, I divided out the triangles into ones pointed up and ones pointed down. I then used different bisectors from the Incentre function to create straight notches on all triangles first. I then polar arrayed the straight notches around the center of the triangles for the other two sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment2/make-notches.png" alt="Making notches for both up and down triangles" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make sure each notch was created out from the midpoint, I used the construct domain function to set expressions to size the straight notches on the xy plane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment2/construct-domain.png" alt="Using Construct Domain to set expressions" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="creating-the-connector-piece"&gt;4. Creating the connector piece&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create the connector piece, I first created a rectangle 4x the size of the notches. Using the construct domain function again, I created inner rectangles aligned to the left and right of the triangle taking the inputs for each material size. I then used the region difference function to create the entire connector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment2/connector.png" alt="Creating straight connectors" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="creating-15-30-and-45-connector-pieces"&gt;5. Creating 15°, 30°, and 45° connector pieces&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I create a new rectangle half the width of the connector and used that to separate it into two sides. To do this, I made sure to set the origin of rotation at the bottom center point of the connector using the Box Corners function to find each corner. I then rotated each connector by increasing amounts of 15°.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment2/angled-connectors.png" alt="Rotating the angled connectors" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To join the left angled side and the right non-angled side, I first separated all the sides. I then found the top right corner of the angled side and the top left corner of the non-angled side, and created a line between the two points. I then joined all three curves, using flatten trees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment2/join-connectors.png" alt="Joining the angled connectors" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="bisecting-the-triangles-to-create-inner-polygons"&gt;6. Bisecting the triangles to create inner polygons&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I baked both the triangles into Rhino and created the bisecting lines by hand to make sure they were all truly unique for each set of triangles. I used a line and checked 'On curve' to make sure it would snap to each inner triangle. I then used trim to select which half I wanted to delete. I then joined all the (now) inner polygon curves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment2/bisecting.png" alt="Inner polygons" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="setting-the-shapes-up-for-printing"&gt;7. Setting the shapes up for printing&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then set the shapes to different layers to allow printing at different settings on different materials. I actually ended up combining the inner polygons and outer triangles to create two sets of shapes so that the acrylic and wood pieces would be different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment2/setting-layers.png" alt="Dividing the shapes into layers for different printing" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="printing"&gt;Printing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had set up my units in Rhino to be in inches to match everything else and checked the 1 to 1 matching on the export box, so I didn't run into any sizing issues like my classmates who were in the Mill at the same time as me. They didn't seem to have an issue once they set everything to inches as well. I actually exported everything to Illustrator so I could be damn sure it would print at the correct size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set up a test layer with four connector pieces in different colors and then color mapped them to a range of values to find the best setting for each material. This also allowed me to test the connection between materials. I found it to be a bit loose at first and reduced the size of the notch rectangles by 0.05 inches for each side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I masked the plywood and left the protective film on the acrylic sheets to reduce the burnt haze on the wood. I probably should've masked the clear sheet since it had only a clear protector and should've masked the back of the plywood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment2/triangles2.gif" alt="Laser cutting more triangles" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Laser cutting is still very satisfying to watch and way easier than hand sawing through this plywood&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment2/IMG_2442.JPG" alt="Triangles" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Pieces all piled up in the makerspace after printing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment2/IMG_2445.JPG" alt="Triangles" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;:D Yay, awesome colors!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/images/assignment2/IMG_2438.JPG" alt="Little Burnt Notches" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Should've masked this sheet, oh well, they’re pretty tiny&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="settings"&gt;Settings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final settings I used to print my materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="clear--neon-acrylic"&gt;Clear &amp;amp; Neon Acrylic&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.06" Thick &amp;amp; .118" Thick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speed: 14, Power: 100, Frequency: 50&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tested both acrylic sheets since their thickness varied, but found the same setting to be good for both. This setting had a very satisfying "snap out" quality on the neon acrylic, which also ensured the pieces didn't all fall below the laser cutter’s grid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="plywood"&gt;Plywood&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0.196" Thick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speed: 10, Power: 100, Frequency: 50&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="future-considerations"&gt;Future Considerations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trimming overlapping triangle lines to reduce duplicate cuts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Masking the clear acrylic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not spending so many damn hours in Grasshopper trying to get it to generate everything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
