<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2019-04-15T23:11:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Laser Cut Kit</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/hcde598/2019/04/16/laser-cut-kit.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/hcde598/2019/04/16/laser-cut-kit.html</id>
    <published>2019-04-15T23:11:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-04-15T23:15:41-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="house-plant--planter-construction-kit"&gt;House Plant &amp;amp; Planter Construction Kit&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to get in on the house plant trend but kill even a snake plant? Why not laser cut one? Guaranteed never to die since it’s made out of cardboard. You’ll never run the risk of forgetting to water it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Just don’t water it. Cardboard is not a living thing.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="building-the-planter"&gt;Building the planter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted a planter shape that turned 2D cardboard into a 3D cylindrical shape. At first, I thought about creating a grid with angled notches to fit squares into a cylinder. This &lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt; have worked, but seemed rather flimsy. I instead thought about turning vertical shapes on an angle to achieve the effect of a planter instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/hcde598/images/laser-1.jpg" alt="Vertical cross-section pieces" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start, I created a basic shape of the diameter cross-section of a planter and accompanied it with two circles with notches to fit all of the vertical shapes together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To acheive a more solid-looking effect, I rotated the notches on the circle 330° to piece together the vertical shapes at an angle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/hcde598/images/laser-4.gif" alt="Vertical cross-section pieces" /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Videos and gifs at 4x speed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then wanted to make sure that all the pieces were aligned on a z-axis, so I added notches to the top and bottom of the vertical planter-profile pieces and removed every other notch from the stablizing circle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="building-the-plant"&gt;Building the plant&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created 10 different leaf varieties to mimic the shape of snake plant leaves. These are tall and the visual effect can roughly be acheived in a 2D plane, which is why they were chosen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I added a long "popsicle stick" at the bottom of the leaf to act as a root through the top circle and through the pot. To stablize this further, I added a third circle and adjusted a third the vertical pieces to move the notch down the center as well as the notches in the circle to remove every third instead of every other. This gives each of the leaf "roots" something to sit on like a nice bed of dirt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/hcde598/images/laser-5.gif" alt="Vertical cross-section pieces" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then choose one circle to act as the top of the plant and drew rectangular cut-outs in a spiral pattern to mimic plant growth. These will be where the popsicle sticks go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="laser-cutting-everything"&gt;Laser cutting everything&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I assembled four artboards sized to cardboard I had pre-cut from a large Lego box and laid out each object to fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/hcde598/images/laser-1.gif" alt="Cutting out the planter circles" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran into an issue where the vertical pieces, even though their stroke was set to the smallest setting, was still wanted to be raster cut by the laser cutter instead of vector cut. I had to re-draw this shape using one of the leaves I knew had already laser cut as vector. I set the laser cutter to 25% power 100% speed, which worked enough to properly cut out everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/hcde598/images/laser-2.gif" alt="Cutting out the leaves" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="assembling-the-final-plant"&gt;Assembling the final plant&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To assemble the plant, first put together the planter. Take one vertical profile piece and slide it into the slots on the three circles with the circle with rectangular cut-outs at the top. Do the same on the opposite side. Then, fill in with vertical pieces around all sides of the circles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/hcde598/images/laser-2.jpg" alt="Cutting out the leaves" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose your leaves. To acheive optimum plant growth, choose taller leaves for the center and smaller leaves on the outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/hcde598/hcde598/images/laser-4.jpg" alt="Cutting out the leaves" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/kfrank/hcde598/blob/gh-pages/documentation/laser-cut-kit/planter.ai"&gt;Download the source illustrator files&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Nameboard</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/hcde598/2019/04/04/nameboard.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/hcde598/2019/04/04/nameboard.html</id>
    <published>2019-04-03T20:19:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-04-15T23:15:41-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the first assignment, I decided to build a stand for a nametag I received while attending &lt;a href="https://greenvillegrok.com/"&gt;Greenville Grok&lt;/a&gt;, an unconference for people who create things online. I attended this conference on April 5th &amp;amp; 6th and had to fly across the country to Greenville, SC. This limited the time I was able to spend actually making something and also limited the tools and materials available to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were given 5 1/4-inch floppy disks as our nametags. I built a stand out of legos since that's what I had available to me at my boyfriend's place. If I had been home for a significant time, I probably would've created something out of wood using my Dremel. The Chewbacca minifig is a special addition, as it has been to space (above the Karman line) on the payload of the most recent &lt;a href="https://www.blueorigin.com/new-shepard/"&gt;Blue Origin New Shepard&lt;/a&gt; mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since nametags were on 5 1⁄4-inch floppy disks, it made me recall the history presented to us in our first class. Like all the inventions that led us to modern fabrication with digital tools, our modern internet technologies have evolved from the storage popular in the 70s and early 80s. Some of those early digital fabrication files were probably saved on a floppy just like this. Moving forward, I think it's important to recognize the achievements of the past, what we can learn from their discoveries, and what we still have yet to learn while building new things.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
